<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://faculty.baruch.cuny.edu/geoportal/metadata/bcgis_dcxml.css"?>
<metadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://faculty.baruch.cuny.edu/geoportal/metadata/bcgis_dc_schema.xsd">
<title>Tax Exempt Organizations in New York City, June 2019</title>
<creator>Frank Donnelly</creator>
<subject>economy</subject>
<subject>society</subject>
<description>This dataset is an extract from the IRS Exempt Organizations file that contains records for non-profit, tax-exempt organizations in New York City that filed 990 forms with the IRS. Most of the organizations in this data file are classified as 501(3)c, which includes most public charities and private foundations. Attributes include organization names, addresses, tax filing status, and income. The data was extracted from the IRS Master File Extract for NY State by selecting all 5-digit ZIP codes located in the five boroughs. The list of ZIP Codes was generated by using resources provided by the Missouri Census Data Center, which included tools for the assignment of US Census ZIP Code Tabulation Areas (ZCTAs) to counties and a crosswalk table for relating ZCTAs to USPS ZIP Codes. The 5-digit ZIP Code and the Census ANSI / FIPS codes for counties were appended to each organization's record, and the city field of the organization's address was cleaned to fix mis-spellings and to standardize names. A separate sheet is included in the dataset with a summary of records by borough and by Exempt Organization Subsection code. Additional information about the dataset is provided in the README tab in the spreadsheet. </description>
<publisher>Newman Library (Bernard M. Baruch College)</publisher>
<issued>2019-06</issued>
<type>Dataset</type>
<format>Tabular Data</format>
<medium>Table</medium>
<identifier>irs_xorgs_june2019_nyc.xls</identifier>
<identifier>https://www.baruch.cuny.edu/confluence/display/geoportal/IRS+Tax+Exempt+Organizations</identifier>
<source>Internal Revenue Service Statistics of Income Division, Exempt Organizations Business Master File Extract</source>
<source>Missouri Census Data Center, Geocorr Application</source>
<language>English</language>
<isPartOf>IRS Tax Exempt Organizations in NYC</isPartOf>
<coverage>New York City, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>Bronx County, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>Kings County, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>New York County, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>Queens County, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>Richmond County, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>Borough of Bronx, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>Borough of Brooklyn, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>Borough of Manhattan, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>Borough of Queens, New York, United States</coverage>
<coverage>Borough of Staten Island, New York, United States</coverage>
<spatial>name=New York City; northlimit=40.915282; eastlimit=-73.700272; southlimit=40.495929; westlimit=-74.255895; units=deg; projection=NAD83;</spatial>
<temporal>2019-06</temporal>
<rights>Public</rights>
<license>Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives CC BY-NC-ND</license>
<license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license>
<provenance>Baruch CUNY</provenance>
<accrualperiodicity>Semiannual</accrualperiodicity>
</metadata>